Jake Derry

Software Developer

Software engineer with training and experience in creating web technologies in Java and Python. Most effective in Agile especially Scrum environments. Inquisitive towards technologies to ensure ethical software development practices. Bright critical thinker who solves problems quickly and supports teammates naturally.

Contact

Address

Durham, NC, 27708

Phone

(706) 691-7888

E-mail

jacob.derry@duke.edu

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jkderry/

Skills

Agile environments



AWS Tools
Web server

development

Strong

Communication

Relational

databases

Observability

Java

Python

Wor

Work History

2020-05 -Current

Software Development Intern

Bandwidth, Inc., Durham, NC

- Developed monitoring platform now used by over 50 developers to replace previous version with improved flexibility, reduced deployment difficulty, and minimized alarming noise using Spring Boot web framework, Datadog, and AWS.
- Contributed to Scrum software development team through writing stories, meeting for regular stand-up, and providing feedback during retrospective.
- Wrote effective documentation which successfully allowed multiple developers to contribute to monitoring platform project.

2020-01 -Current

Web Developer

Duke Computer Science Design, Durham, NC

- Architected REST API and backend system redesign of existing system to allow increased flexibility using Spring Boot and Hibernate.
- Employed Agile practices to this project team which experiences quick turn-over because it consists of student developers to produce fast prototypes, prove architectural decisions, and keep track of evolving requirements of system used by over 50 students and around 10 teaching assistants.

2018-08 -Current

Teaching Assistant

Duke Computer Science, Durham, NC

 Lead code reviews with students to identify areas of concern within their projects during development to determine that their Java projects could scale with changing requirements of this course.

Education

2017-08 -Current

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Duke University - Durham, NC